Guide to the Stanford University Objects Collection SC1048
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Objects
  - Portrait of Thad Sigourney, ARCH-AM-00-018 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, B&W Photgraph, by Bradley Ruloson '93, S.F. Oval Format 76x66 cm., wooden frame 104x91 cm., under glass., ARCH-AM-00-078 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Daivd Starr Jordan, 1913. 38"x50"in., ARCH-AM-00-336 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Elizabeth Phillips Stanford- Leland's mother., ARCH-AM-00-350 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, John Casper Branner, c. 1913. 48x40cm., ARCH-AM-00-337 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Judge Samuel Lieb. 67x48cm., ARCH-AM-00-335 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Mark Hopkins., ARCH-AM-00-349 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, oil, David Starr Jordan, by Spencer Macky, 1922, framed. frame 110x92 cm, image 113x122 cm., ARCH-AM-00-280 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, oil: Ray Lyman Wilbur, c. 1943, ARCH-AM-00-338 (Box 1)
  - Portrait, Senator Leland Stanford, Oval., ARCH-AM-00-348 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Anna Maria Lathrop Hewes, ARCH-AM-00-347 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Donald B. Tresidder, ca. 1950, ARCH-AM-00-339 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: J. E. Wallace Sterlling, 1971, ARCH-AM-00-341 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Josiah Stanford, Sr., ARCH-AM-00-346 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Kenneth Pitzer, ca. 1970, ARCH-AM-00-340 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Leland Stanford, Jr.; oil in gold frame, ARCH-AM-00-345 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Mark Hopkins, ARCH-AM-00-344 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Richard W. Lyman, ARCH-AM-00-342 (Box 1)
  - Portrait: Timothy Hopkins, ARCH-AM-00-343 (Box 1)
  - Post Office Boxes, ARCH-AM-00-108 (Box 1)
  - Poster (art work) cartoon, man at piano (on cardboard). 73x49 cm. Ink and pastel., ARCH-AM-00-312 (Box 1)
  - Poster (art work) cartoon, man at radio microphone (on cardboard). 73x49 cm. Ink and pastel., ARCH-AM-00-314 (Box 1)
  - Poster (art work) cartoon, man dressed as a king with V sign (on cardboard). 73x49 cm. Ink and pastel., ARCH-AM-00-311 (Box 1)
  - Poster (art work) cartoon, man in football uniform (on cardboard). 73x49 cm. Ink and pastel., ARCH-AM-00-313 (Box 1)
  - Poster - Barry Goldwater for President. 3.5 x 4.5 ft., ARCH-AM-1997-017 (Box 1)
  - Poster board with examples of table finishes and upholstery materials and two photographs of furniture for the activities center, Graduate School of Business, Stanford University, [1970s from look of the furniture], ARCH-AM-2006-012 (Box 1)
  - Poster on cardboard. 56X36 cm. Blue and Gold, 1903, bu Jr. Class of Univ. of California., ARCH-AM-00-154 (Box 1)
  - Poster; Driving the Golden Spike, ARCH-AM-00-315 (Box 1)
  - Presented to Stanford University from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration. Flag and crew patch flown aboard space shuttle Columbia 1990, with photographs. Signed by G. David Low, Stanford class of 1983. 40.5 cm x 50.5 cm, ARCH-AM-1994-15 (Box 1)
  - Presidential Medal of Freedom awarded to Siemon William Muller for work on permafrost, 1946; ARCH-AM.2015-004 (Box 1)
  - Press pass for Gorbachev's talk, May 9, 1992 (#187), ARCH-AM-1995-06 (Box 1)
  - Pressboard binder from the Stanford Bookstore, ca. 1950 (originally with accn 2002-020). With LSJU seal embossed on lower right corner and embossed elaborate border for title area., ARCH-AM-2002-08 (Box 1)
  - Print of the Spencer Macky Portrait of David Starr Johnson, framed, with glass. Enscribed by Jordan. ("with kind regards"), ARCH-AM-1984-06 (Box 1)
  - Printing block (metal on wood), 2.5 x 1.5 inches, for the movie "Spirit of Stanford" 1942, ARCH-AM-2002-02 (Box 1)
  - Printing block for Jewel Fund bookplate: copper plate on wood block, ARCH-AM-2003-018 (Box 1)
  - Printing die - view of Mem Church through arch "Stanford Memorial Church" beneath, ARCH-AM-1981-14 (Box 1)
  - Printing dies of the University seal, the tree symbol, and the Stanford "S", circa 1950; ARCH-AM-2009-015 (Box 1)
    9 dies of the University Seal, assorted sizes 2 dies of the tree symbol 1 die of the Stanford "S"
  - Printing plate for biographical information on Grayson N. Kefauver, with several sketches; signed "Stratton '35", ARCH-AM-2005-046 (Box 1)
  - Printing Plate; Stanford Library. 25X34X2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-187 (Box 1)
  - Printing plate: portrait of William D. Briggs, ARCH-AM-1992-04 (Box 1)
  - Printing plates for music (4); at least one is from the 1905 DECENNIAL OF STANFORD SONG (includes paper print from each one), ARCH-AM-1996-05 (Box 1)
  - Printing plates for text and illustrations of M. Bailey's book Seven Peas in the Pod, ARCH-AM-2002-11 (Box 1)
    boxes 1-12 are text plates (some with illustrations also); box 13 is illustration plates on wooden blocks
  - Proclamation signed by Governor Ronald Reagan regarding Transcontinental Railroad Centennial Day, May 10, 1969. Framed, ARCH-AM-2001-07 (Box 1)
  - Promotion materials for book "Stanford Sports", ARCH-AM-1983-08 (Box 1)
    1. T-shirt: tan, with football player "Stanford Sports" size 34-36, polyester, cotton 2. Button: 8x5.5cm with "Stanford Sports" and color photograph of football players (#10)
  - Scarf (purple and white stripes) and unused "indecks Research Deck" (punch card system for sortable notes), ARCH-AM-2006-003 (Box 1)
    2006-003.01 scarf 2006-003.02 research deck
  - Quilt, approx. 10 x 10 feet, 1993; ARCH-AM-2008-006 (Box 1)
  - Quilt, approx. 87" x 104", red background with 25 hand-stitched blocks depicting various scenes and symbols of Stanford., circa 1972-1984; ARCH-AM-2015-014 (Box 1)
    One of several quilts created by Stanford Medical Faculty Women's Association, circa 1972-1984.
  - Quilts (12) made by HAAS students, 1994-2005; ARCH-AM-2006-037 (Box 1)
    Box 1: 2006-037.1 Class of 1994 2006-037.2 Class of 1995 2006-037.3 Class of 1996 Box 2: 2006-037.4 Class of 1997 2006-037.5 1998 2006-037.6 1999 2006-037.7 [untitled] 2000 Box 3: 2006-037.8 2001 2006-037.9 [untitled] 2002 2006-037.10 2003 2006-037.11 2004 2006-037.12 2005
  - Ransome concrete form - boards; discovered during 1997 renovation. 4.5 ft. x 5.5 ft., ARCH-AM-1997-014 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Dartmouth College LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.15 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Hood, University of California., ARCH-AM-00-188.3 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Hood: Duke University LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.5 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Hood: Syracuse ScD, ARCH-AM-00-188.2 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Hood: Univ. of Arizona LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.4 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: New York University LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.7 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Princeton Univ. LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.12 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Scd. Western Reserve, ARCH-AM-00-188.1 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Tusculum College LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.6 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Univ. of Chicago LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.8 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Univ. of New Mexico LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.11 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Univ. of Pennsylvania LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.16 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Univ. of Pittsburgh LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.14 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Univ. of Rochester LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.10 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Univ. of State of new York (Albany) LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.9 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, honorary degree hood: Yale Univ. LLD, ARCH-AM-00-188.13 (Box 1)
  - Razor Strop. Used by Encina Barber, (19?, 16x6 cm. strop with metal end,), ARCH-AM-00-118 (Box 1)
  - Red & white ribbon with rosette used at dedication of Language Center building (Bldg 30) on 5/8/97, ARCH-AM-1997-006 (Box 1)
  - Red apron and ID tag from SULA book sale, circa 1995; ARCH-AM-2009-032 (Box 1)
    2009-032.1 red apron 2009-032.2 ID tag: "Book Sale Associate" in plastic holder with chain
  - Red balloon in plastic box. 9x6x5. Dated 7/8/76, balloon imprinted with Starts (Student Arts at Stanford)., ARCH-AM-00-239 (Box 1)
  - Red cloth band with "STANFORD '54" [use unknown - not a hat band], ARCH-AM-1999-023 (Box 1)
  - Red felt "Stanford" banner with seal in right corner and "27" in left corner, ARCH-AM-1993-16 (Box 1)
  - Red felt banner with white trim and lettering, "Stanford" with seal taken into space by Sally Ride on the U.S. space shuttle Challenger, June 18-24, 1983., ARCH-AM-1984-09 (Box 1)
  - Red felt banner: "Stanford" in white letters, ARCH-AM-1990-001 (Box 1)
  - Red felt football (8 1/4" long) with white printed letters: "Stanford" and laces, ARCH-AM-1982-06 (Box 1)
  - Red felt pennant with "1937" in red letters. RETURNED TO CASPER 4/3/2002, ARCH-AM-00-022 (Box 1)
  - Red foam Axe: Stanford Axe Committee Give 'Em The Axe, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-038 (Box 1)
  - Red knit athletic jersey, '01, ARCH-AM-00-060 (Box 1)
  - Pillow (leather), with fringe. Has block "S" in white leather pasted on and some flowers in white leather pasted on, circa 1907; ARCH-AM-1989-071 (Box 1)
  - Red men's tie, with hand painted "lil Injun" in white, ARCH-AM-00-034 (Box 1)
  - Polo shirt, emblem: STANFORD NCAA 2001 SWEET SIXTEEN, ARCH-AM-2005-048 (Box 1)
  - Red ribbon and scissors used at grand re-opening of Green Library Bing Wing, October 12, 1999., ARCH-AM-1999-020 (Box 1)
  - Silk scarf - hemmed square with white "S" in center (15 in.), ARCH-AM-2007-023 (Box 1)
  - Red sponge axe with "Stanford Axe Commitee Give 'Em The Axe" and the Stanford S with superimposed tree., ARCH-AM-2002-09 (Box 1)
  - red sweater "1905" on chest, ARCH-AM-2002-18 (Box 1)
  - Red sweatshirt with "AXE" in white letters, ARCH-AM-2002-21 (Box 1)
  - Red wool blanket with embroidered "LSJU" in center; used by Pres. Wilbir in Encina dorm room., ARCH-AM-1980-06 (Box 1)
  - Red wool cheerleading sweater belonging to Chesley Douglas, cardigan style, ARCH-AM-1999-013 (Box 1)
  - Relief Bust of Ray Lyman Wilbur - 58x41 cm, "3rd Pres. of Stanford"(in 6' crate), ARCH-AM-00-080 (Box 1)
  - Replica (mold?) of plaque for James Grant Fergusson, A.B. 1908, 2nd Lieutenant in the Eighth Black Watch, Killed in Action at Longueval France 14 July 1916. (23.5 x 18 in.) Mounted on plywood (36 x 31 in.), ARCH-AM-2006-014 (Box 1)
  - Replica of 1887 trowel from cornerstone laying - presented to James C. Gaither; with original box, ARCH-AM-1997-008 (Box 1)
  - Replica of 1887 trowel from cornerstone laying - presented to Lawrence V. Ryan 1991 (trowel is 94 of 100), ARCH-AM-00-008 (Box 1)
  - Replica of 1887 trowel from cornerstone laying - presented to Michael H. Walsh; with original box, ARCH-AM-1997-009 (Box 1)
  - Replica of Gold Spike; 14x15 cm on stand made from old R.R. Tie., ARCH-AM-00-238 (Box 1)
  - Replica of trowel used at S.U. cornerstone laying.; #1 of 100; w/ flannel bag., ARCH-AM-1995-12 (Box 1)
  - Reproduction of Portrait of Jane Stanford/ o.d. 115x100 cm. Tinted, gold frame., ARCH-AM-00-260 (Box 1)
  - Research Corp. Award to Wm Martin Fairbank, ARCH-AM-1978-04 (Box 1)
  - Rhumbatron, ARCH-AM-1996-14 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon from luncheon at the White House Feb. 27, 1886: image of the White House on one end, Mrs. Stanford's name on the other. [Invitation for this event in SC 033b, Series 3, Box 1], ARCH-AM-2005-001 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon with artificial flowers, following written on individual streamers: Mr. Stanford California Apr. 28 '91. Unknown event/purpose, ARCH-AM-2004-023 (Box 1)
  - Ribbon: Stanford stadium marshall number 10 Stanford v. California Nov. 19, 1921, ARCH-AM-1993-09 (Box 1)
  - Ribbons of the Stanford Parlor No. 76 N.S.G.W., 1886 and ca. 1899, ARCH-AM-2004-016 (Box 1)
    016.1 Admission Day, San Jose, 1886 - guest ribbon (faded pink) 016.2 Admission Day, San Jose, 1886 - dark blue 016.3 Stanford Parlor No. 76 with images of Leland Stanford, front of Quad, and unidentified harbor; possibly dated 1899. Attached to metal relief pin at top
  - Road Sign: Alvarado and Escondito, ARCH-AM-00-066 (Box 1)
  - Rock from quarry taken during 1994 tour, ARCH-AM-1994-12 (Box 1)
    (see ref. accn. 94-169)
  - Roof tile (clay) from Memorial Church, post 1906, ARCH-AM-1997-023 (Box 1)
  - Roos Bros megaphone, circa 1945?; ARCH-AM-2003-016 (Box 1)
  - Rooter button, "Stanford", 1924; ARCH-AM-1977-07 (Box 1)
  - Rooters' cap (red felt beanie), circa 1945?; ARCH-AM-2003-017 (Box 1)
  - Rose Bowl button and Stanford decal (with Lil Injun figure), ARCH-AM-2004-013 (Box 1)
    013.1 Rose Bowl button 013.2 Stanford decal (with Lil Injun figure)
  - Round fans on wooden stick, from Orientation events, ARCH-AM-1998-019 (Box 1)
    AM 98-019.1 and .2 1997 Orientation "Hail, Stanford, Hail!" over picture of inner quad AM 98-019.3 and .4 1998 "Hail, Stanford, Hail!" over the seal; reverse: Opening Convocation program
  - Round table, inlaid top, carved legs; said to belong to Jane Stanford and given by her to Lawrence Joseph Connolly during a home remodel, ARCH-AM-1998-002 (Box 1)
  - Royal typewriter, ARCH-AM-1985-11 (Box 1)
  - Rubber stamps (for cancellation) with Stanford Centennial graphics/text, 1991, ARCH-AM-2004-004 (Box 1)
    2004-004.1 "Stanford Centennial Convocation Oct. 1, 1991" 2004-004.2 "Stanford Centennial Celebration homecoming parade Sept. 29, 1991" 2004-004.3 "Stadium Spectacular Sept. 30, 1991" 2004-004.4 "Stanford vs. Colorado Sept. 28, 1991"
  - Rug, Stanford Seal, Accession ARCH-AM-2018-008 (Box 1)
    Rug, latch hook, with Stanford Seal in red on white background.
  - Runner, Brown, 150X71cm. Fringe on short side. Small red S on each end., ARCH-AM-00-136 (Box 1)
  - S. U. and Stanford Indian memorabilia, ARCH-AM-1992-14 (Box 1)
    see listing in accn files for 1992-092
  - T-shirts (6): class of '80; Toyon and Branner Halls; Hopkins Marine Station, 1979-80; ARCH-AM-1997-010 (Box 1)
  - Sample impression from Leland Stanford's seal [intertwined L and S], ARCH-AM-1994-16 (Box 1)
  - Sample of hair felting used as acoustical insulation in Memorial Church (installed ca. 1910, removed 1981), ARCH-AM-2004-029 (Box 1)
  - Samples of bricks and tile salvaged from Palo Alto depot during reconstruction, ARCH-AM-2005-025 (Box 1)
    025.1 original bricks @P5F1 025.2 tile from restrooms 025.3 section of floor tile ""W-floor""
  - Samples of wall paper found in/on Branner Hall during renovation, Fall 2002 (5 items), ARCH-AM-2003-021 (Box 1)
  - Sandstone tablet on Redwood base with inscription "Mikhail Gorbachev, June 4, 1990.", ARCH-AM-1993-17 (Box 1)
  - Screen. 46X172 cm. Burlap and tapestry on top., ARCH-AM-00-148 (Box 1)
  - Seat cushion "Sunset Salutes Stanford University for a Century of Achievement" with the Centennial logo, ARCH-AM-2008-002 (Box 1)
  - Seat cushion, Big Game (ARCH-AM-1997-019.3), ARCH-AM-1997-019.3 (Box 1)
  - Seat cushions, athletics, 1985-2000; ARCH-AM-2016-009 (Box 1)
    - Seat cushion from Super Bowl, 1985; ARCH-AM-2016-009.01 (Box 1)
    - Seat cushion from Big Game, 1997; ARCH-AM-2016-009.02 (Box 1)
    - Seat cushion from Rose Bowl, 2000; ARCH-AM-2016-009.03 (Box 1)
  - Seat cushion given out at women's final four basketball championships in Cincinnati, 1997., ARCH-AM-2007-009 (Box 1)
  - See Card File. Verify against item, ARCH-AM-00-129 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll '44, ARCH-AM-00-041 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll '48, ARCH-AM-00-042 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll, '36, ARCH-AM-00-044 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll, '39, ARCH-AM-00-043 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll, '40, ARCH-AM-00-050 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll, '43, ARCH-AM-00-051 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll, '52, ARCH-AM-00-053 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll, '53, ARCH-AM-00-055 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll, '54, ARCH-AM-00-054 (Box 1)
  - Senior Class roll, '55, ARCH-AM-00-052 (Box 1)
  - Senior Sombrero '08. G.C.H. on inner band; B. Halsey written inside crown, ARCH-AM-1997-013 (Box 1)
  - Senior sombrero of O. Wayne Mulford '24. Felt field hat by Stetson, leather band with "1924" and "O W M" on sweat band; sold by Roos Bros., ARCH-AM-1977-11 (Box 1)
  - Senior sombrero of Richard Frey. Felt field hat by Stetson, leather band with "Stanford 1924", ARCH-AM-1977-12 (Box 1)
  - Senior sombrero of William A. Ray. Ribbon band; brand mark of John B. Stetson Company on inner sweatband & store mark of Wideman's, ARCH-AM-2005-009 (Box 1)
  - Senior sombrero, leather band "Stanford '09", ARCH-AM-1993-12 (Box 1)
  - Senior sombrero. Felt field hat by Stetson, cloth band, no date, with "C M" on sweat band, ARCH-AM-1977-13 (Box 1)
  - Sexploration: A Game Designed to Promote Thoughtful Discussion, Factual Learning, and Responsible Decision Making about Sex, Drugs, Alcohol, and Relationships (board game), ARCH-AM-2012-001 (Box 1)
  - Shot classes (2) from 1990 and 1991 and coffee mug from Branner Advising Team '01-'02, ARCH-AM-2006-002 (Box 1)
    2006-002.01 shot glass 1990 2006-002.02 shot glass 1991 2006-002.03 Coffee mug
  - Shovel: Green Library groundbreaking, wood handle with bronzed metal spade and handle 40" long., ARCH-AM-1980-24 (Box 1)
  - Shovel: Ruth Wattis Mitchell Earth Science Building;ground breaking- Aug. 19, 1968; Stanford University. 40" high, ARCH-AM-1982-05 (Box 1)
  - Shirt, "Hawaiian" style, Accession ARCH-AM-2018-013 (Box 1)
    Shirt pattern includes: palm trees, palm fronds, phtographs of the quad, as well as "Cardinal Courses," "Greater Service," "Cardinal Careers," "Be of Greater Service,""Cardinal Service" and "Beat Cal" pennants.
  - Sigma Chi fraternity paddle, 1934; ARCH-AM-2003-015 (Box 1)
  - Sign, accordian fold, two sided. 29x69 cm. Red side: "Go Stanford! The 2013 Rose Bown Game" with Rose Bowl Game/Presented by Vizi Logo/Stanford Alumni Block S/Tree insigna. Black side: Stanford tree mascot depiction with white picket fence., ARCH-AM-2015-007 (Box 1)
  - Sign, cardboard. "Room 310- University Archives" 18x55cm., ARCH-AM-00-333 (Box 1)
  - Sign, framed. "Room 311 Archives Reading Room" frame 28x35cm., ARCH-AM-00-332 (Box 1)
  - Sign: "Hopkins Railway Library" white painting on black metal. 8x45 cm., ARCH-AM-00-267 (Box 1)
  - Silkscreen pattern used for the etched glass shades of the historic pendant light fixtures in building 01-30 [made in France], ARCH-AM-2001-23 (Box 1)
    Due to its size, it is currently housed in regular cardboard.
  - Silver case for calling cards given as a wedding gift to Mrs. Van Alstyne from Leland Stanford, with leather carrying case, ARCH-AM-2003-001 (Box 1)
  - Silver cup with "LS" monogram and "44", alleged to have been Leland Stanford's., ARCH-AM-1998-018 (Box 1)
  - Silver pitcher presented to Leland Stanford, ARCH-AM-00-011 (Box 1)
  - Silver pitcher presented to Leland Stanford by State Agricultural Society for best Holsteins, 1887; ARCH-AM-00-009 (Box 1)
  - Silver pitcher presented to Leland Stanford for "Elaine", for best 4-yr old record, 1878; ARCH-AM-00-010 (Box 1)
  - Silver tea set (Reed & Barton) used at Roble Hall prior to 1989; each piece stamped (engraved?) with a shield, Roble Club, Stanford University California [held for safe keeping by Porteus while Roble was undergoing earthquake reinforcements], ARCH-AM-2005-047 (Box 1)
    2005-047.1 sugar bowl 2005-047.2 sugar bowl 2005-047.3 cream pitcher 2005-047.4 cream pitcher 2005-047.5 footed serving bowl (7 in. diam.) 2005-047.6 footed serving bowl (7 in. diam.) 2005-047.7 tea pot 2005-047.8 tea pot 2005-047.9 footed round serving platter (11 in.) 2005-047.10 footed round serving platter (11 in.) 2005-047.11 footed round serving platter (11 in.) 2005-047.12 serving tray 2005-047.13 serving tray
  - Silver trophy presented to Norman Dole for world's record pole vault, 1904, by UC students, Stanford-Cal meet. Sterling silver, ARCH-AM-1977-10 (Box 1)
  - Silver vase presented to Willis, 1913, in recognition of friendship from "Comision de Estudios Hidrologicos,Buenos Aires, Argentina" (in square case, lined)., ARCH-AM-1995-09 (Box 1)
  - Silver-plated spoon with "L.S.Jr. University" on handle, ARCH-AM-1992-05 (Box 1)
  - Slice from a limb of oak tree by Mausoleum that was cut down in 1993, ARCH-AM-1993-10 (Box 1)
  - Slide rule used by Hansen, in case., ARCH-AM-1995-26 (Box 1)
  - Small Banner, 17x11 cm. Red felt with white "S"., ARCH-AM-00-196 (Box 1)
  - Small clipboard and ink blotter, both made from hammered metal (brass or copper), both decorated with university seal. Clipboard bears imprint of Robbins Co., Attleboro, MA, ARCH-AM-2001-27 (Box 1)
    AM 2001-27.1 clipboard AM 2001-27.2 blotter
  - Small red banner (blank), pointed ends - purpose unknown, ARCH-AM-2004-022 (Box 1)
  - Snow globe featuring Stanford University scene, undated; ARCH-AM-2010-010 (Box 1)
    Snow globe: 6.5 inches tall, interior features Hoover Tower, Red Barn, Stadium, The Dish, Memorial Church, the Oval, Red hoop sculpture, and others not so easily identified. Base has version of university seal (no motto).
  - Solar cell and silicon chip from Engineering Library display, undated; ARCH-AM-2008-025 (Box 1)
    2008-025.1 Silicon solar cell in case with attached wiring 2008-025.2 Silicon chip on metal strip which is wrapped around 2nd metal piece 2008-025.3 large square plastic magnifier
  - Sombrero. Soft grey felt hat (brim not as wide as usual); signatures of friends under brim., 1910; ARCH-AM-1981-11 (Box 1)
  - Sophomore College t-shirts, 2009; ARCH-AM-2009-041 (Box 1)
    2009-041.1 "Practicing Creativity" brown shirt with orange lettering 2009-041.2 "Practicing Creativity" red shirt with orange lettering 2009-041.3 "Sophomore College 2009" dark green shirt; list of classes on back 2009-041.4 "Sophomore College 2009" light green shirt; list of classes on back
  - Sophomore College t-shirts, ARCH-AM-2010-013 (Box 1)
    2010-013.1 Sophomore College 2001 - red with "SOCO 2001" on back 2010-013.2 Sophomore College 2003 - white with "SoCo 2003" on front and "Oh, the Places You Can Go in SoCo!" on back 2010-013.3 Sophomore College 2004 - black with "18 days + 22 Professors + 284 students" on front and list of names on back 2010-013.4 Sophomore College 2005 - green with "SoCo 2005" and Hoover Tower on front 2010-013.5 Sophomore College 2007 - white with "What level are you trying to reach" on front and list of classes on back 2010-013.6 Bing Honors College A September Studies Program 2010 - purple 2010-013.7 arts intensive A September Studies Program 2010 - maroon 2010-013.8 Sophomre College 2010
  - Sophomore College T-shirts (2), 2002, 2006; ARCH-AM-2009-005 (Box 1)
    2009-005.1 - T-shirt: Stanford Sophomore College 2006 [on back: SOCO 06 Stanford Sophomore College 2006] 2009-005.2 - T-shirt: Sophomore College 2002 [on back: Stanford University]
  - Sophomore dink, ARCH-AM-1981-04 (Box 1)
  - Souvenir matchbook (intact), 13" long illustrated w/ buildings and map inside, ARCH-AM-1995-28 (Box 1)
  - Souvenir matchbook cover 32.5cm long x 5cm, ARCH-AM-1982-04 (Box 1)
  - Souvenir of Stanford University: metal cup with raised images of Mem Chu, entrance gate, Mem Arch, quad arcade, Palo Alto tree. (same as AM 00-192), ARCH-AM-2003-019 (Box 1)
  - Souvenir pennant of the U.S.S.R. - U.S.A. track meet at Stanford Stadium (9 inches long), circa 1962; ARCH-AM-2001-26 (Box 1)
  - Souvenir spoon: Memorial Arch, circa 1905; ARCH-AM-1980-22 (Box 1)
  - Souvenir: plastic viewer and key chain. View of Mem Chi. 5x2cm., ARCH-AM-1980-15 (Box 1)
  - Spode plates (12) with Stanford scenes, 1943; ARCH-AM-2016-011 (Box 1, Box 3)
    ARCH-AM-2016-011.01--ARCH-AM-2016-011.12: 12 Spode plates
  - Spode plates (13) with Stanford scenes, ARCH-AM-1978-09 (Box 1)
  - Spode plates (7) with Stanford scenes: Jordan Hall, between classes, union, arches and library, memorial church, administration building, library front, ARCH-AM-1995-020 (Box 1)
  - Spode plates with Stanford scenes, ARCH-AM-1989-057 (Box 1)
  - Spoon - sketch of front view of Quad [pre-1906] and "Stanford Jr. University" in bowl; CA state seal and "California" on handle, ARCH-AM-2006-017 (Box 1)
  - Spurr, old, 12 X 5 cm., ARCH-AM-00-145 (Box 1)